自上次以来你有看到或者听到什么东西吗？
没有。
果然是这样吧！
这都是心理状态导致的，玲音。
我想你应该不会再看到它们了。不过如果又看见了，别太沮丧。
总会逐渐治愈的。
还不能立刻治好吗？
嗯…我也不清楚。玲音开始有这些问题的时候是多大岁数？
十一岁。
所以已经有一年多了。在这段时间里，“它们”大概出现了多少次？
我不记得了…很多次。
Sometimes, even if there doesn't seem to be an explanation for it immediately, these things may go away.
But if you decide that they’ve gone away completely and become complacent, there’s a chance that they may come back.
I can’t say for certain that that will happen with you, but even if you don’t see them for a while, I’d like you to continue what you’ve been doing up till now.
Do you want to stop coming here, Lain?
No. I like seeing you.
谢谢。
I guess that there’s no problem, then.
You’re doing well, but you’ll promise me that you will keep coming here?
Yes. In exchange, I want you to teach me some things.
欸？
For homework?
当然。
You won’t believe it, but I was pretty sharp in junior high school.
Ha, ha.
Learning to read and write was tough, though.
I don’t mean that. I want to know more about your work. Is that okay?
Hmm.
I don't think it’s a very good idea, but if you’re really curious, okay. Learning about things that make you curious is a great way to study.
But you have to make time for your schoolwork, too.
I’ll promise to teach you about my work if you promise to do your schoolwork.
Can you promise me that?
Yes, I promise.
And if you break your promise...
I’ll whack you with a blowfish!